Suleiman Yusuf Gacheru

Full Stack Software Developer

Nairobi, Kenya

Email: dretrevor8@gmail.com Phone No. +254110579100

Github|Linkedin|

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with high interest in Cyber Security and a love for Project Management . Embrace and excel in the realm of Software Development, Cyber Security Ethics (CIA) Triad and Information Security. Proficient in multiple languages, frameworks and technologies like Ruby on Rails, React and JavaScript. Experienced in pair programming and remote work, quick to adapt. Fast learner and multitasker

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, BootStrap.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork.

Deployment Environment: Render, Netifly

Project Management Tools: Asan, Spreadsheets, WBS

Operating Systems: Linux Os, Windows OS, Virtual Machines

EXPERIENCE

Hetroxity Desktop Support and Network Technician, May 2024 - Present

As a Freelance IT Technician, I diagnose and repair hardware and software issues on client desktops and laptops, and configure and troubleshoot home networks. I provide comprehensive technical support and advice to clients to enhance their IT infrastructure.

- Diagnose and repair hardware and software issues on client desktops and laptops.
- Configure and troubleshoot home networks, including Wi-Fi setup and security.
- Provide technical support and advice to clients on improving their IT infrastructure.
- Perform routine maintenance to ensure optimal performance of client systems.
- Maintain accurate records of services provided and manage client communications.

Tech -A-Intern Remote Web Developer, March 2024 - April 1 2024

Full Stack Software developer at an indian remote based company, responsible for building dynamic web applications and implementing additional features upon request and revamping the website to better streamline operations

- Developed and implemented both front-end and back-end components of web applications, adhering to project requirements.
- Orchestrated in-depth collaboration with senior engineers to analyze and dissect project requirements,

- ensuring seamless integration with project goals; facilitated a 20% decrease in development time through precise alignment strategies.
- Wrote clean and efficient code following coding standards and best practices, contributing to the overall quality and maintainability of the applications.
- Integrated user-facing elements seamlessly with server-side logic, enhancing user experience and functionality.
- Stayed abreast of industry best practices and agile development methodologies, incorporating new technologies to optimize project outcomes

Office Assistant - Internship, April 2023 - December 2023

MINISTRY OF YOUTH AFFAIRS, CREATIVE ECONOMY AND SPORTS STATE DEPARTMENT FOR YOUTH AFFAIRS

Supported daily Operations and facility management at a sub-urban government office, ensuring ongoing support for ~200 citizens, as well as providing empowerment opportunities information regarding organization partners throughout the year, including Commencement (~200 attendees)

- Managed daily office operations with minimal supervision, ensuring smooth functioning and efficiency.
- Facilitated access to learning opportunities offered by partnered organizations, empowering youths and increasing participation by 25%
- Ensured accuracy and completeness of loan applications for local citizens, resulting in a 45% improvement in database reliability through meticulous application processing..
- Streamlined data entry procedures for youth group loan applications, resulting in a 25% reduction in processing time; integrated data validation techniques to maintain data integrity and confidentiality standards at all times

EDUCATION

GOOGLE CAREER CERTIFICATE SCHOLARSHIP- Coursera, Self-paced January 2024 - Present.

- 1. Project Management Professional Certificate
- 2. Cyber Security Professional Certificate

MICROVERSE Remote Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time May 2023 – Dec 2023

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.